<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection><source>PMC</source><date>20140719</date><key>pmc_ascii.key</key><document><id>2150581</id><passage><infon key="article-id_pmc">2150581</infon><infon key="article-id_pmid">10087265</infon><infon key="fpage">1219</infon><infon key="issue">6</infon><infon key="journal-title">The Journal of Cell Biology</infon><infon key="kwd">kinesin microtubules molecular motors cytoskeleton Saccharomyces cerevisiae</infon><infon key="lpage">1233</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Manning;given-names:Brendan D.</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Barrett;given-names:Jennifer G.</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wallace;given-names:Julie A.</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Granok;given-names:Howard</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Snyder;given-names:Michael</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">144</infon><infon key="year">1999</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Differential Regulation of the Kar3p Kinesin-related Protein by Two  Associated Proteins, Cik1p and Vik1p </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>107</offset><text>The mechanisms by which kinesin-related  proteins interact with other proteins to carry out specific cellular processes is poorly understood. The kinesin-related protein, Kar3p, has been implicated in many  microtubule functions in yeast. Some of these functions  require interaction with the Cik1 protein (Page, B.D.,  L.L. Satterwhite, M.D. Rose, and M. Snyder. 1994. J.  Cell Biol. 124:507-519). We have identified a Saccharomyces cerevisiae gene, named VIK1, encoding a protein  with sequence and structural similarity to Cik1p. The  Vik1 protein is detected in vegetatively growing cells  but not in mating pheromone-treated cells. Vik1p physically associates with Kar3p in a complex separate from  that of the Kar3p-Cik1p complex. Vik1p localizes to the  spindle-pole body region in a Kar3p-dependent manner. Reciprocally, concentration of Kar3p at the spindle  poles during vegetative growth requires the presence of  Vik1p, but not Cik1p. Phenotypic analysis suggests that  Cik1p and Vik1p are involved in different Kar3p functions. Disruption of VIK1 causes increased resistance to  the microtubule depolymerizing drug benomyl and partially suppresses growth defects of cik1Delta mutants. The  vik1Delta and kar3Delta mutations, but not cik1Delta, partially  suppresses the temperature-sensitive growth defect of  strains lacking the function of two other yeast kinesin-related proteins, Cin8p and Kip1p. Our results indicate  that Kar3p forms functionally distinct complexes with  Cik1p and Vik1p to participate in different microtubule-mediated events within the same cell.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1682</offset><text>Microtubules are a component of all eukaryotic  cytoskeletons and are essential for many diverse  cellular and intracellular movements, such as  flagellar motility, organelle positioning, vesicle trafficking,  mitotic spindle orientation, and chromosome segregation.  Two families of chemomechanical motor proteins, dynein  and kinesin-related proteins, are crucial for these microtubule functions (Vale et al., 1985; Schnapp and Reese, 1989;  Steuer et al., 1990; reviewed by Vale and Fletterick, 1997;  Hirokawa, 1998). These proteins possess highly conserved  motor domains responsible for movement along microtubules (Yang et al., 1990). The nonmotor portion of these  proteins links the motor domain to a vast array of cargoes  or localizes the motor to various subcellular sites (Yang  et al., 1989; Afshar et al., 1995; Wittmann et al., 1998).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2533</offset><text>The family of proteins sharing a region of homology  with the motor domain of conventional kinesin-heavy chain  (KHC)1 has grown enormously in recent years (reviewed  by Hirokawa, 1996; Moore and Endow, 1996). These kinesin-related proteins (KRPs) have been identified in all eukaryotes from yeast to humans. KRPs vary in directionality and the position of their motor domains. Most KRPs,  as well as conventional kinesin, have NH2-terminal motor  domains and travel toward the more dynamic plus ends of  microtubules. Others have internally located motor domains and may also have plus-end polarity. Another subfamily of KRPs have COOH-terminal motors and travel  toward the less dynamic minus ends of microtubules, the  end generally associated with microtubule-organizing centers. Whereas KRPs share a high degree of sequence similarity within their motor domains, the remainder of their  primary sequences are highly divergent. These variable regions are thought to interact with different proteins to mediate the functional specificity of the motor (Page et al.,  1994). Recent studies have unveiled many details about  the molecular structure and function of kinesin-like motor  domains (Hirose et al., 1995, 1996; Arnal et al., 1996; Kull  et al., 1996; Sablin et al., 1996; Gulick et al., 1998), but far  less is known about how these proteins are regulated and  what other components are involved in their function.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3958</offset><text>Aside from the light chains of conventional KHC, few  other kinesin-associated proteins (KAPs) have been identified. In many organisms, KHCs associate with various  isoforms of kinesin-light chains (KLCs) to form complexes  involved in transport of organelle and vesicle populations  (Cyr et al., 1991; Beushausen et al., 1993; Gauger and  Goldstein, 1993; Wedaman et al., 1993; Khodjakov et al.,  1998; Rahman et al., 1998). Additionally, KHC has been  shown to tightly associate with both a KLC kinase and a  KLC phosphatase that putatively regulate motor function  (McIlvain et al., 1994; Lindesmith et al., 1997). Two KAPs  that interact with specific KRPs have also been identified.  The KIF3 heterodimeric class of KRPs, also known as  kinesin-II, interact with a single KAP to form a heterotrimeric complex (Cole et al., 1993, 1998; Scholey, 1996; Wedaman et al., 1996; Yamazaki et al., 1996). Finally, a Saccharomyces cerevisiae KRP, Kar3p, has been shown to  associate with the Cik1 protein, which is essential for  Kar3p localization and function during mating (Page et al.,  1994).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>5051</offset><text>The Kar3 protein is one of six KRPs encoded by the  S. cerevisiae genome (Meluh and Rose, 1990). KAR3 encodes a protein containing a kinesin-motor domain at its  COOH terminus (Meluh and Rose, 1990). The Kar3p-motor domain possesses minus-end directionality and microtubule-depolymerizing activity in vitro (Endow et al.,  1994). In addition to an essential role in nuclear fusion  during mating, or karyogamy, Kar3p has been implicated  in several microtubule functions during the vegetative cell  cycle. These putative functions include spindle assembly,  mitotic chromosome segregation, microtubule depolymerization, kinetochore-motor activity, spindle positioning,  and as a force opposing the action of other KRPs (Meluh  and Rose, 1990; Roof et al., 1991; Saunders and Hoyt,  1992; Hoyt et al., 1993; Endow et al., 1994; Middleton and  Carbon, 1994; Cottingham and Hoyt, 1997; DeZwaan et  al., 1997; Saunders et al., 1997a,b; Huyett et al., 1998). This  presents an interesting problem: how can one motor protein perform such a diverse array of functions within a single cell?</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>6134</offset><text>The role of Cik1p during mating is to target Kar3p to  cytoplasmic microtubules (Meluh and Rose, 1990; Page  et al., 1994). Kar3p and Cik1p are interdependent for  their localization to the SPBs and cytoplasmic microtubules of cells treated with mating pheromone (Page et  al., 1994). Expression of KAR3 and CIK1 is increased  upon exposure to pheromone, but both genes are also  expressed during vegetative growth (Meluh and Rose,  1990; Page and Snyder, 1992; Kurihara et al., 1996).  Cik1p is also involved in a subset of Kar3p's vegetative  functions. kar3Delta and cik1Delta mutants share several vegetative phenotypes, including a growth defect at 37 C,  enhanced cytoplasmic microtubules, very short mitotic  spindles, and an accumulation of large budded cells indicative of a mitotic cell-cycle checkpoint delay (Meluh  and Rose, 1990; Page and Snyder, 1992; Page et al.,  1994). They also share genetic interactions with several  genes (Manning et al., 1997). Furthermore, Cik1p requires  Kar3p for its mitotic spindle localization (Page et al., 1994),  and the two proteins coimmunoprecipitate from vegetative cell lysates (Barrett, J.G., B.D. Manning, and M. Snyder,  unpublished data).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7327</offset><text>However, unlike during mating, Kar3p does not require  Cik1p for its localization to the spindle poles in mitosis  (Page et al., 1994; this study). This suggests that Kar3p has  some Cik1p-independent functions. Genetic studies support this hypothesis. Kar3p is believed to oppose the force  generated by two other S. cerevisiae KRPs, Cin8p and  Kip1p, which are involved in spindle pole separation both  during spindle assembly and during anaphase B spindle  elongation (Hoyt et al., 1992, 1993; Roof et al., 1992; Saunders and Hoyt, 1992; Saunders et al., 1995). Disruption of  KAR3 function partially rescues the temperature-sensitive  growth defect and spindle collapse phenotype of cin8ts  kip1Delta mutants (Saunders and Hoyt, 1992; Hoyt et al.,  1993). In contrast, disruption of CIK1 does not rescue this  mutant (Page et al., 1994; this study). Together, these results suggest that Kar3p may perform some of its vegetative functions alone or in association with a different KAP.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8312</offset><text>In this study we describe a Cik1p-homologous protein in  S. cerevisiae that acts as a second KAP for Kar3p. We  demonstrate that this protein, Vik1p (vegetative interaction with Kar3p), is present in vegetatively growing cells  but absent from mating-pheromone treated cells. Vik1p  forms a complex with Kar3p that is distinct from that  between Kar3p and Cik1p. Furthermore, we show that  Kar3p and Vik1p are interdependent for their concentration at the poles of the mitotic spindle. Phenotypic and  genetic comparisons of cik1Delta and vik1Delta mutants demonstrate that Cik1p and Vik1p are likely to mediate distinct  subsets of Kar3p functions. Our data suggest that Cik1p  and Vik1p regulate Kar3p function, at least in part, by targeting the motor to various sites of action within the cell.  This is the first example of two distinct associated proteins  differentially regulating a single KRP.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>9209</offset><text>Materials and Methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>9231</offset><text>Strains, Media, and Standard Methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9268</offset><text>S. cerevisiae strains used in this study are listed in Table I. Yeast growth  media, molecular biological techniques, and genetic manipulations were  as described previously (Sambrook et al., 1989; Guthrie and Fink, 1991).  Yeast transformation procedures were performed using the lithium acetate method (Ito et al., 1983). Where indicated, rich medium, consisting of  yeast extract, peptone, and dextrose, was supplemented with benomyl  (DuPont), dissolved in DMSO, to a final concentration of 10, 20, or 30 mug/ml.  Sensitivity of wild-type yeast strains to these concentrations of benomyl  varied between preparations of benomyl containing agar plates and,  hence, growth comparisons were always performed on the same plate.  Sensitivity also varies dramatically between growth temperatures (i.e., at  23 C strains are much more benomyl sensitive than at 30 C). </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>10136</offset><text>Construction of VIK1::3XHA Strain</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>10170</offset><text>A strain containing the VIK1::3XHA allele (Y1744) was constructed by  the PCR-epitope tagging method described previously (Schneider et al.,  1995). The primers 5'-TATTAACGATTTCAGAAGAAGTTCAAACACAACTTTGTAAAAGAAAGAAAAAGCTCACTAGGGAACA-AAAAGCTGG-3' and 5'-CTTATTTGTTTCATATCTAAATGGCTGTG TTAAGAAAGACGATAATG TGACCGAGC TTAC TATAGG-GCGAATTGG-3' were used in a PCR reaction with pMPY-3XHA as the  template. The resulting 1.5-kb PCR product contains the URA3 gene  flanked by direct repeats encoding three copies of the hemagglutinin  (HA) epitope and contains 59 bp of sequence from the 3' end of the VIK1  gene at one end and 59 bp of sequence downstream of, and including, the  VIK1 translation termination codon at the other end. This fragment was  used to transform yeast strain Y1731, and transformants were selected on  synthetic complete medium lacking uracil. Correct integration into the 3'  region of the VIK1 locus was confirmed by PCR analysis with primers to  sequences flanking the site of insertion. Transformants with a correct  3XHA-URA3-3XHA integration were then incubated on plates containing 5-fluoroorotic acid to select for loss of the URA3 marker by recombination between the repeated 3XHA regions. The resulting VIK1::3XHA  allele was confirmed by PCR and immunoblot analysis. This allele does  not display any vik1Delta phenotypes; growth of VIK1::3XHA strains in the  presence of benomyl is identical to wild-type strains, and the temperature-sensitive growth defect of cik1Delta mutants is the same in a VIK1 or VIK1:: 3XHA background.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>11730</offset><text>Immunoprecipitations and Immunoblot Analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>11775</offset><text>Cells were grown in rich liquid medium to mid-logarithmic phase (OD600 =  0.5-0.8), and a total of 10 OD600 units of cells were collected by centrifugation, washed, and resuspended in 100 mul lysis buffer (1 M NaCl, 10 mM  EDTA, 2 mM EGTA, 5% glycerol, 40 mM Tris-HCl, pH 7.5, containing  1 mul yeast protease inhibitor cocktail (Sigma Chemical Co.) and 200 muM  PMSF). When indicated, cells were first washed twice with fresh medium,  resuspended in medium containing 5 mug/ml alpha-factor mating pheromone  (Sigma Chemical Co.), and incubated for 2 h before harvesting. Cell lysates were prepared in Eppendorf tubes using zirconia/silica beads (Biospec Products) with 40-s pulses of vortexing separated by incubations on  ice; this procedure was repeated 6-8 times. Lysates were then centrifuged  for 10 min at 6,500 g, and a 10-mul aliquot was removed for immunoblot  analysis.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12657</offset><text>For immunoprecipitations, the remaining cell lysate and beads were  washed with 500 mul lysis buffer containing detergents (1% NP-40, 0.5%  sodium deoxycholate, and 0.1% SDS) without NaCl for 20 min on a roller  drum at 4 C. Lysates were then cleared of unlysed cells and cell debris by  centrifugation for 10 min at 6,500 g and ~500 mul of supernatant was transferred to a new tube. The 500 mul lysate was brought to a 1-ml vol with the  same lysis buffer plus detergents (100 mM final NaCl concentration). The  cell lysate was then precleared for 1 h by incubation with 20 mul of a 1:1  slurry of protein A/G-agarose (Pierce) and TBS (150 mM NaCl, 50 mM  Tris-HCl, pH 8.0). Immunoprecipitations were performed by incubation  of cell lysates with either 2 mul mouse monoclonal anti-HA antibodies  (12CA5 from BABCO), 10 mul rabbit polyclonal anti-Cik1p antibodies  (Page and Snyder, 1992), or 5 mul rabbit polyclonal anti-Kar3p antiserum  (gift of L.L. Satterwhite, P.B. Meluh, and M.D. Rose, Princeton University, Princeton, NJ; Meluh and Rose, 1990; Page et al., 1994) for 2 h. 20 mul  protein A/G-agarose was then added and incubated for 1 h before collection by centrifugation at 2,000 g for 1 min. The protein A/G-agarose antibody complexes were then washed twice with 1 ml TBS containing detergents and protease inhibitors (1% NP-40, 0.5% sodium deoxycholate,  0.1% SDS, 1 mul Sigma yeast protease inhibitor cocktail, 200 mM PMSF)  and once with 1 ml TBS plus protease inhibitors. The final pellet was resuspended in 30 mul Laemmli sample buffer (Laemmli, 1970).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>14236</offset><text>Proteins from cell lysates and immunoprecipitations were denatured by  incubation at 90 C for 10 min before electrophoretic separation in either  8% or 10% SDS-polyacrylamide gels. For attempts to detect Vik1p-3XHA in mating-pheromone treated cells, a threefold larger volume of  cell lysate was loaded than for vegetative cell lysates (data not shown).  Proteins were then transferred to Immobilon-P membranes (Millipore)  for immunoblot analysis with either mouse monoclonal anti-HA antibodies (12CA5 from BABCO), rabbit polyclonal anti-Cik1p antibodies (Page  and Snyder, 1992), or a crude IgG fraction of the rabbit polyclonal anti-Kar3p antiserum (Meluh and Rose, 1990; Page et al., 1994). Reactive protein bands were then detected with alkaline phosphatase-conjugated  secondary antibodies (Amersham) and the CDP Star detection reagent  (Boehringer Mannheim). Overexposure of all blots failed to detect Vik1p-3XHA in cell lysates from mating-pheromone treated cells.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>15212</offset><text>Fluorescence Microscopy</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>15236</offset><text>Indirect immunofluorescence was performed as described previously  (Gehrung and Snyder, 1990; Pringle et al., 1991). Due to sensitivity of the  HA-epitope to formaldehyde fixation, mid-logarithmic phase cells were  fixed with 3.7% formaldehyde for only 15 min. They were then washed  twice with solution A (1.2 M sorbitol, 50 mM potassium phosphate buffer,  pH 6.8), and spheroplasts were prepared by incubating cells in solution A  containing 5 mug/ml Zymolyase 100T, 0.03% glusulase, and 0.2% 2-mercaptoethanol at 37 C for 15 to 30 min. Spheroplasted cells were then  washed and resuspended in solution A and placed onto poly(l-lysine)- coated slides. Vik1p-3XHA and Kar3p-HAT were detected by incubation  overnight at 4 C with preabsorbed mouse monoclonal anti-HA primary  antibodies (16B12 from BABCO) diluted in PBS/BSA. Bound mouse  anti-HA antibodies were then detected by incubation for 90 min at room  temperature with preabsorbed CY3-conjugated goat anti-mouse secondary antibodies (Jackson ImmunoResearch Laboratory, Inc.). Microtubules were detected by incubation with rabbit anti-yeast beta-tubulin  (Tub2p) primary antibodies (gift of F. Solomon, Massachusetts Institute  of Technology; Bond et al., 1986) followed by incubation with FITC-conjugated goat anti-rabbit secondary antibodies. After both primary and  secondary antibody incubations, slides were washed twice with PBS/BSA  and twice with PBS/BSA plus 0.1% NP-40. Finally, slides were mounted  in 70% glycerol, 2% n-propyl gallate, and 0.25 mug/ml Hoechst 33258 to  preserve the preparation and stain DNA for localization of nuclei.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16845</offset><text>Photographs of representative cells stained with anti-HA antibodies,  anti-Tub2p antibodies, and/or Hoechst 33258 were taken, and composite  figures were produced and processed using Adobe Photoshop version 3.0  (Adobe Systems, Inc.). Processing procedures were identical for each  photo of a particular staining method within a composite figure.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>17192</offset><text>Construction of KAR3::HAT Strains</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17226</offset><text>A strain containing the KAR3::HAT allele was constructed using a transposon insertion technique described previously (Ross-MacDonald et al.,  1997). The entire KAR3 coding region was cloned into the vector pHSS6  and subjected to transposon mutagenesis in Escherichia coli as described  (Ross-MacDonald et al., 1997). Plasmid DNA was prepared from selected  strains and digested with NotI, producing a fragment containing the mTn-3xHA/lacZ transposon inserted randomly into the KAR3 gene. These  fragments were then used to transform yeast strain Y1869, using the  URA3 marker encoded by the transposon for selection. Transformants  with in-frame transposon insertions into the KAR3 genomic locus were selected by detection of beta-galactosidase activity as described (Burns et al.,  1994). Cre recombinase-mediated excision, leaving only the 93 amino acid  HA/transposon tag (HAT) inserted, was induced by growth on galactose  (pB227 contains cre under control of a galactose-inducible promoter). Recombinants were selected on 5-fluoroorotic acid. Strains with in-frame  HAT insertions were then tested for kar3Delta mutant phenotypes, such as  defects in karyogamy and temperature sensitivity. PCR and sequence  analysis was performed on DNA from fully complementing strains in order to determine the site of insertion within the KAR3 gene.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>18564</offset><text>Strain Y1870 contains a KAR3 allele with a HAT insertion after the  codon for S68, and does not exhibit any kar3Delta phenotypes. Y1870 was then  crossed with Y1864 to yield Y1871. Y1871 was then sporulated and a  MATalpha KAR3::HAT cik1Delta::LEU2 segregant (Y1751) was isolated. The  VIK1 gene was disrupted with the HIS3 marker in Y1870 yielding Y1752  (see below). Y1752 was then crossed with Y1751 yielding Y1753. Y1753  haploid segregants were used to analyze Kar3p-HAT localization in wild-type, cik1Delta, vik1Delta, and cik1Delta vik1Delta strains.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>19101</offset><text>Cloning of VIK1 and Disruption of VIK1, CIK1, and KAR3</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>19156</offset><text>Sequence of the VIK1 gene was acquired from the Saccharomyces Genome Database (ORF designation YPL253c; Stanford University). A  2,920-bp region, from the MscI site 5' of the predicted VIK1 translation  start site to the SpeI site 3' of the VIK1 translation termination site, was  PCR amplified from yeast genomic DNA and cloned into pBluescript SK  (Stratagene), replacing its EcoRV-SpeI fragment (pSK-VIK1). The SalI-SacII fragment from this plasmid, containing the VIK1 gene and flanking  sequences, was cloned into the SalI-SacII site of the CEN plasmid pRS316  (Sikorski and Hieter, 1989). This plasmid was linearized by deleting the  NruI-AflII fragment containing the entire VIK1 ORF, then gap repaired  in a wild-type yeast strain (Guthrie and Fink, 1991). This CEN plasmid encoding wild-type VIK1 was used for subsequent phenotypic analysis.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20011</offset><text>VIK1 disruption constructs were made by replacing the NruI-AflII  fragment of pSK-VIK1 with the SmaI fragment from either pJA50 (HIS3-Kmr) or pJA53 (URA3-Kmr) (Elledge and Davis, 1988). SalI-XbaI fragments from these plasmids, containing either the HIS3 or URA3 selectable markers flanked by the 5' and 3' noncoding regions of VIK1, were  used to transform yeast strains Y270, Y818, and Y1870 yielding vik1Delta  strains Y1733, Y1748, and Y1752, respectively.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20472</offset><text>CIK1 and KAR3 disruptions were made as previously described (Page  and Snyder, 1992; Page et al., 1994). The cik1-Delta3::LEU2 construct was  used to transform strains Y817 and Y1744 yielding cik1Delta strains Y1758  and Y1745, respectively. The kar3-Delta4::URA3 construct was used to transform strains Y818 and Y1744 yielding kar3Delta strains Y1759 and Y1750, respectively.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>20837</offset><text>Results</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>20845</offset><text>Vik1p: A Cik1p Homologue Present in Vegetative Cells  but Not in Cells Treated with Mating Pheromone</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20946</offset><text>A database homology search with the Cik1p amino acid  sequence identified an open reading frame (ORF) on chromosome XVI of the S. cerevisiae genome (BLAST search  of predicted translation products of S. cerevisiae ORFs;  Saccharomyces Genome Database ORF designation  YPL253c) predicted to encode a protein with significant  homology to Cik1p. This gene was named VIK1, for vegetative interaction with Kar3p (see below). VIK1 is predicted to encode a protein of 647 amino acids, with an  overall sequence identity of 24%, and similarity of 37%, to  Cik1p. The Vik1p sequence also shares structural similarity to Cik1p. It contains a predicted alpha-helical coiled-coil  domain (amino acids 80-385) of the same length and location as that found in Cik1p (amino acids 81-388; Page and  Snyder, 1992; Fig. 1; predicted with COILS version 2.2;  Lupas et al., 1991; Lupas, 1996); both proteins contain a  short break of 40 amino acids in their coiled-coil regions.  This break and an 80 residue NH2-terminal globular domain are the most divergent regions of the two proteins  (16% identity). One notable difference in the amino terminal domain is that Vik1p lacks a recognizable nuclear  localization signal found in Cik1p (amino acids 24 to 33;  Fig. 1; Barrett, J.G., and M. Snyder, manuscript in preparation). Finally, the COOH-terminal  globular domains of  the two proteins share two regions of 134 and 43 amino  acids in length with 25% identity each. Therefore, Vik1p  shares sequence and structural homology to Cik1p which  is not confined to their coiled-coil domains. </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>22521</offset><text>To characterize the Vik1 protein by immunoblot and  immunofluorescence analysis, DNA encoding a triple HA-epitope tag was integrated into the COOH-terminal  coding region of the VIK1 genomic locus (see Materials and  Methods). The resulting VIK1::3XHA fusion allele fully  complements VIK1 function (see Materials and Methods).  Immunoblot analysis using anti-HA monoclonal antibodies detects a protein of 92-kD in cell lysates and anti-HA  immunoprecipitations from VIK1::3XHA strains (Fig. 2  A). This molecular mass is close to the predicted 76-kD of  Vik1p plus the triple-HA epitope tag. This fusion protein  is not detected in cell lysates or anti-HA immunoprecipitations from VIK1 untagged strains (Fig. 2 A). Therefore, the VIK1::3XHA allele is expressed during vegetative growth and produces a functional protein of the  expected size. </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>23367</offset><text>The Vik1p-3XHA protein is not detected in cell lysates  or anti-HA immunoprecipitations from cultures first exposed to the alpha-factor mating pheromone (Fig. 2 A; see  Materials and Methods). In contrast, Cik1p greatly increases in abundance upon exposure to alpha-factor (Fig. 2 B;  Page and Snyder, 1992). Consistent with this result, the  region upstream of the VIK1 ORF does not contain any  predicted pheromone-response elements (Kronstad et  al., 1987). However, the pheromone-inducible CIK1 and  KAR3 genes each contain multiple pheromone-response  elements in their 5' noncoding regions (Meluh and Rose,  1990; Page and Snyder, 1992). Thus, since Vik1p is not  present during mating-pheromone induced differentiation,  it is not likely to have a significant role during mating.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>24150</offset><text>Vik1p Coimmunoprecipitates with Kar3p</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>24188</offset><text>Cik1p physically associates with Kar3p (Page et al., 1994),  and Vik1p shares sequence and structural similarity to  Cik1p; we therefore tested whether Vik1p could also interact with Kar3p. Cell lysates were prepared from wild-type,  kar3Delta, and cik1Delta strains expressing either the VIK1:: 3XHA allele or untagged VIK1. Proteins from these cell  lysates were separated by SDS-PAGE (Fig. 3 A) or first  immunoprecipitated with anti-Kar3p polyclonal antibodies (Fig. 3 B; Meluh and Rose, 1990; Page et al., 1994).  Immunoblot analysis using anti-HA antibodies detects  Vik1p-3XHA in cell lysates from wild-type, kar3Delta, and  cik1Delta strains containing the VIK1::3XHA allele but not in  untagged strains (Fig. 3 A). Therefore, Vik1p stability is  not affected by the absence of either Kar3p or Cik1p.  Anti-HA immunoblots of proteins immunoprecipitated  with anti-Kar3p antibodies detects Vik1p-3XHA from a  wild-type VIK1::3XHA strain but not from a kar3Delta VIK1:: 3XHA strain or an untagged strain (Fig. 3 B). Therefore,  immunoprecipitation data indicate that Kar3p and Vik1p  physically interact. Furthermore, the Kar3p-Vik1p complex is quite stable, as cell lysates were prepared in a 1 M  NaCl solution (see Materials and Methods). </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>25422</offset><text>Vik1p-3XHA is also detected in anti-Kar3p immunoprecipitations from a cik1Delta VIK1::3XHA strain (Fig. 3 B),  indicating that Cik1p is not required for this interaction  between Kar3p and Vik1p. Furthermore, an association  between Vik1p and Cik1p is not detected by immunoprecipitation experiments. Vik1p-3XHA is not precipitated  from VIK1::3XHA cell lysates by anti-Cik1p polyclonal  antibodies (Fig. 2 A; Page and Snyder, 1992; Page et al.,  1994), and, reciprocally, Cik1p is not precipitated from  these cell lysates with anti-HA antibodies (Fig. 2 B). Protein preparations from vegetatively growing cells or alpha-factor-treated cells produce the same results. Thus, Vik1p  and Cik1p do not appear to be part of the same complex.  Together, these results suggest that Vik1p and Cik1p interact with Kar3p separately, and, therefore, form two different complexes during vegetative growth.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>26313</offset><text>Vik1p Localizes to the Spindle-Pole Bodies</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>26356</offset><text>To determine the subcellular localization of Vik1p, asynchronous cultures of VIK1::3XHA and VIK1 untagged  strains were fixed briefly with formaldehyde and analyzed  by immunofluorescence using anti-HA and anti-tubulin  antibodies (see Materials and Methods). VIK1::3XHA cells  display anti-HA staining concentrated at the yeast microtubule-organizing centers, or spindle-pole bodies (SPBs),  in all stages of the cell cycle (Fig. 4, B and C). The position  of the SPBs correspond to the brightest foci of anti-tubulin  staining. Anti-HA staining at the SPBs is not detected in  VIK1 untagged cells (Fig. 4 A). Moreover, detection of  Vik1p-3XHA at the SPBs does not require costaining with  anti-tubulin antibodies; staining of dots at the edges of  both preanaphase and anaphase nuclei is still observed in  control cells not stained with anti-tubulin antibodies (Fig.  4 C). Vik1p-3XHA staining is brightest in preanaphase  cells with short spindles, where localization is clearly concentrated at the spindle poles (pattern observed in 100%  of preanaphase spindles; n &gt; 200; Fig. 4 B). Cells in the G1  phase of the cell cycle, scored as unbudded cells with a single SPB, display SPB staining that is more faint and not  observed in every cell (staining observed in 60% of G1  cells; n = 100). Finally, cells in early or late anaphase, as  scored by elongated spindles and/or elongated nuclei penetrating the bud neck, display faint staining concentrated  at the spindle poles (staining of at least one spindle pole is  observed in 73% of anaphase cells; n = 100; Fig. 4 C, inset). Anti-HA staining is not detected along the lengths of  spindle or cytoplasmic microtubules in VIK1::3XHA cells.  Short fixation times due to sensitivity of the HA-epitope  to formaldehyde leads to a diminished number of cytoplasmic microtubules. However, in cells that contain cytoplasmic microtubules, only staining at the SPBs is observed; microtubule staining is not evident. These staining  patterns are independent of ploidy, and the nature and position of the epitope tag. VIK1::3XHA/VIK1::3XHA homozygous diploids, and cells expressing a VIK1::3Xmyc  NH2-terminal fusion allele stained with anti-myc monoclonal antibodies, exhibit identical patterns to those found  in VIK1::3XHA haploid cells (data not shown). </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>28662</offset><text>The localization of Vik1p at, or near, the SPBs at various levels throughout the vegetative cell cycle is very similar to that reported for fusion proteins of Kar3p with either  beta-galactosidase or HA (Page et al., 1994; Saunders et al.,  1997; see below). However, in pheromone-treated cells,  when Kar3p localizes to the SPB and cytoplasmic microtubules (Meluh and Rose, 1990; Page et al., 1994), Vik1p-3XHA staining above background is not detected (data  not shown). This is consistent with immunoblot data demonstrating the absence of Vik1p in cell lysates from alpha-factor-treated cells (Fig. 2 A), and further suggests that Vik1p  functions in vegetative cells, but not mating cells.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>29353</offset><text>Spindle-Pole Body Localization of Vik1p is Kar3p Dependent</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>29412</offset><text>Since Kar3p and Vik1p physically associate and have similar localization patterns, we investigated whether the  localization of Vik1p to the SPBs was dependent on the  presence of Kar3p. Therefore, Vik1p-3XHA localization  was analyzed by anti-HA immunofluorescence in kar3Delta  cells. Whereas Vik1p-3XHA concentrates at the SPBs in  wild-type cells, it does not localize to the SPBs at any stage  of the cell cycle in the kar3Delta mutant. Instead, the protein  is present in cytoplasmic patches that appear to be excluded from the nucleus (SPB staining was not detected in  any cells; n &gt; 300; a representative preanaphase cell is  shown in Fig. 5 B). This pattern is also observed with anti-myc staining in kar3Delta cells containing the VIK1::3Xmyc  allele (data not shown). These cytoplasmic patches are not  detected in kar3Delta VIK1 untagged strains (Fig. 5 A). SPB  localization of Vik1p-3XHA can be restored by introducing a CEN plasmid containing KAR3 into the kar3Delta VIK1:: 3XHA strain (Fig. 5 C). This plasmid also restores normal  spindle length, since disruption of KAR3 results in accumulation of cells with short spindles compared with wild-type cells (Meluh and Rose, 1990). Therefore, the Kar3p-Vik1p association is required for localization of Vik1p to  the SPB. </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>30685</offset><text>Cik1p also localizes to the SPB in a Kar3p-dependent  manner (Page et al., 1994), and, like kar3Delta mutants, cik1Delta  mutants accumulate cells with short mitotic spindles (Page  and Snyder, 1992). Therefore, in order to determine if  Cik1p was involved in localizing Vik1p to the SPB or if the  short spindle phenotype was responsible for Vik1p mislocalization in kar3Delta mutants, we analyzed Vik1p-3XHA localization in a cik1Delta mutant. In contrast to kar3Delta cells,  cik1Delta cells display Vik1p-3XHA staining concentrated at  the SPBs during all stages of the cell cycle, as observed in  wild-type cells. Furthermore, HA staining is brightest at  the poles of the short preanaphase spindles present in  cik1Delta cells (a representative cell is shown in Fig. 5 D), indicating that the short spindle phenotype alone is not the  cause of mislocalization of Vik1p. Therefore, these immunolocalization data support the immunoprecipitation experiments; Vik1p does not appear to be part of the same  complex as Cik1p. Furthermore, Vik1p localization to the  SPBs does not require Cik1p function.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>31768</offset><text>Proper Spindle-Pole Body Localization of Kar3p in  Vegetative Cells Is Vik1p Dependent</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31855</offset><text>Cik1p is required to localize Kar3p to the SPB and cytoplasmic microtubules during mating but is not required for  Kar3p localization to the mitotic spindle poles (Page et al.,  1994). This suggests that in vegetative cells, Kar3p can either target to the SPBs by itself or interacts with another  protein that is responsible for its concentration at the  SPBs. Based on its localization and association with Kar3p,  Vik1p could fulfill this function. Therefore, Kar3p was  localized in the absence of Vik1p, Cik1p, and both Vik1p  and Cik1p.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>32398</offset><text>The subcellular localization pattern of Kar3p has been  determined previously using fusion proteins that do not  fully complement all of the kar3Delta phenotypes (Meluh and  Rose, 1990; Page et al., 1994; Saunders et al., 1997). To create a fully complementing HA epitope-tagged version of  Kar3p, we used a transposon insertion technique described  previously (Ross-MacDonald et al., 1997; see Materials  and Methods). Using this technique we created several  strains containing in-frame insertions of the HAT into random regions of the KAR3 genomic locus. We then tested  these strains for several kar3Delta phenotypes, such as defects  in karyogamy and meiosis, slow growth, temperature-sensitive growth, enhanced cytoplasmic microtubules, and the  ability to properly localize Vik1p-3Xmyc to the SPBs (Meluh and Rose, 1990; Page et al., 1994; Bascom-Slack and  Dawson, 1997; Saunders et al., 1997a). Fully complementing alleles were sequenced and found to lie within the region encoding the NH2-terminal globular domain of Kar3p  (data not shown). A strain containing one of these KAR3:: HAT alleles (encoding Kar3p with the 93-amino acid  HAT insertion at S68) was used for immunofluorescence  analysis with anti-HA antibodies.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>33627</offset><text>Localization of Kar3p-HAT was examined in wild-type,  cik1Delta, vik1Delta, and cik1Delta vik1Delta strains. Asynchronous  cultures of haploid segregants from a cik1Delta/CIK1 vik1Delta/ VIK1 KAR3::HAT/KAR3::HAT diploid strain were fixed  and prepared for immunofluorescence with anti-HA and  anti-tubulin antibodies (see Materials and Methods). KAR3::  HAT wild-type cells, in all stages of the cell cycle, display  anti-HA staining concentrated at the SPB region, as well  as faint patches confined to the nucleus (as determined by  colocalization with anti-tubulin and Hoechst staining, respectively). These fluorescence patterns are not observed  in KAR3 untagged strains, in which background staining is  restricted to the cytoplasm (Fig. 6 A). Consistent with previous Kar3p localization studies (Page et al., 1994; Saunders et al., 1997), Kar3p-HAT staining is brightest at the  poles of preanaphase spindles (Fig. 6 B; Table II). Most  cells in G1 (80%, 100 G1 cells counted) and anaphase  (86%, 100 anaphase cells counted) also display Kar3p-HAT localization at the SPBs, but this staining is fainter  than that observed in preanaphase cells (data not shown).  In contrast to previous studies, Kar3p-HAT localization  along spindle microtubules is not detected in any stage of  the cell cycle. When cytoplasmic microtubules are observed, in wild-type cells or the mutant cells described below, Kar3p-HAT localization is not detected along their  lengths. Hence, Kar3p is most abundant at the SPBs of  cells throughout the cell cycle.  </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>35154</offset><text>The effect of disrupting Vik1p and Cik1p function on  Kar3p-HAT localization was determined. Since wild-type  localization is most obvious in preanaphase cells, we quantified Kar3p-HAT staining patterns in cells from asynchronous cultures at this stage (Table II). Similar to wild-type  strains, KAR3::HAT cik1Delta cells display anti-HA staining  at the SPBs during all stages of the cell cycle; again, the  brightest staining is observed at the poles of the preanaphase spindle (Fig. 6 C; Table II). However, the nuclear  patch staining detected in wild-type cells is qualitatively  diminished in the cik1Delta mutant. Therefore, as described  previously (Page et al., 1994), Cik1p is not required to localize Kar3p to the SPBs during the vegetative cell cycle.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>35912</offset><text>In contrast, Kar3p-HAT localization during vegetative  growth is dramatically altered in vik1Delta cells (Fig 6 D; Table II). Kar3p-HAT is no longer concentrated at the SPBs  in these cells; instead, it predominantly displays a bright  nuclear patch localization in all vik1Delta cells. Moreover,  staining along the lengths of spindle microtubules is detected in many cells (34% of preanaphase cells; Fig 6 D;  Table II). Some vik1Delta cells also display faint staining in  the vicinity of the SPBs, but not along spindle microtubules (22% of preanaphase cells; Table II). Therefore, although vik1Delta cells may retain some Kar3p at the SPBs,  Vik1p is required to concentrate, or restrict, Kar3p localization to the SPBs.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>36626</offset><text>To determine if the spindle and faint SPB localization of  Kar3p detected in vik1Delta cells is due to Cik1p function, we  localized Kar3p-HAT in a cik1Delta vik1Delta double mutant.  Kar3p-HAT localization is even more aberrant in the double mutant, with the nuclear patch staining distributed  more diffusely throughout the nucleus in all cells (representative preanaphase cell shown in Fig. 6 E). Detection of  Kar3p-HAT along the spindle or at the SPBs in these cells  is greatly reduced compared with the vik1Delta mutant (spindle and faint SPB localization is observed in 7 and 9%, respectively, of cik1Delta vik1Delta preanaphase cells; Table II). Introduction of a CEN plasmid encoding VIK1 into either  vik1Delta or cik1Delta vik1Delta mutants completely restores Kar3p-HAT concentration at the SPBs (data not shown).  Therefore, during vegetative growth, Vik1p is primarily  responsible for SPB targeting, or retention, of Kar3p.  Cik1p may mediate Kar3p localization to less concentrated sites within the nucleus, such as the spindle and/or  nuclear patches.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>37669</offset><text>CIK1 and VIK1 Disruptions Result in Distinct Phenotypes</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>37725</offset><text>Cik1p and Vik1p exhibit differences in their expression  patterns, and deletion of CIK1 or VIK1 results in unique  effects on Kar3p localization. Therefore, the phenotypes  resulting from disruption of VIK1 and CIK1 were compared. Suprisingly, vik1Delta mutants grow similar to wild-type strains at all temperatures. Using a sectoring assay  described previously (Spencer et al., 1990), we determined  that, unlike cik1Delta mutants that have a severe chromosome  loss defect (Page and Snyder, 1992), vik1Delta mutants display  only a threefold increase in frequency of chromosome loss  per cell division relative to wild-type strains (data not  shown). Furthermore, consistent with its absence in mating-pheromone treated cells, vik1Delta mutants are not defective in karyogamy, as determined by qualitative mating  assays. However, compared with wild-type strains, vik1Delta  mutants are resistant to the microtubule-depolymerizing  drug benomyl (on plates containing 10, 20, or 30 mug/ml  benomyl; 10 mug/ml in Fig. 7 C). The benomyl resistance  phenotype always segregates with the vik1Delta mutation (11  tetrads analyzed). </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>38837</offset><text>To analyze whether CIK1 and VIK1 are functionally  redundant, we tested whether expression of VIK1 from  a high copy plasmid could suppress the temperature-sensitive growth defect of a cik1Delta mutant. cik1Delta strains  containing either the VIK1 plasmid or vector alone are  equally affected by growth at the restrictive temperature  (data not shown). A cik1Delta mutant was then mated with a  vik1Delta mutant, and the resulting heterozygous diploid  strain was sporulated. Haploid segregants from tetratype  tetrads were then analyzed (eight tetrads analyzed; results  from a representative tetrad are shown in Fig. 7). Wild-type, cik1Delta, vik1Delta, and cik1Delta vik1Delta segregants all display  similar growth on rich medium at 23 C (Fig. 7 A). However, cik1Delta mutants are temperature sensitive for growth  at 37 C (Page and Snyder, 1992), whereas vik1Delta mutants  grow like wild-type strains (Fig. 7 B). Suprisingly, cik1Delta  vik1Delta double mutants grow substantially better at 37 C  than cik1Delta mutants (Fig. 7 B). This result indicates that  disruption of VIK1 partially suppresses the temperature-sensitive growth defect of cik1Delta mutants. The temperature-sensitive growth defect can be restored to a cik1Delta  vik1Delta double mutant by introduction of a CEN plasmid  encoding VIK1 (data not shown). Deletion of VIK1 also  partially suppresses the mitotic delay of cik1Delta mutants, as  scored by the percentage of large budded cells with a single preanaphase nucleus in logarithmic phase cultures  growing at 30 C (Fig. 7 D). 54% of cells from cik1Delta cultures exhibit the mitotic delay phenotype, whereas only  36% of cells from cik1Delta vik1Delta cultures have this phenotype. Wild-type and vik1Delta cultures each have 22% large  budded cells. These strains were also analyzed for growth  differences in the presence of benomyl (Fig. 7 C). Unlike  vik1Delta mutants, which display increased resistance to  benomyl, cik1Delta and cik1Delta vik1Delta mutants are slightly more  sensitive than wild-type strains. Therefore, the phenotypic  differences of cik1Delta and vik1Delta mutants, combined with  their different effects on Kar3p localization, suggest that  Cik1p and Vik1p are functionally distinct.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>41004</offset><text>The microtubules of the different mutant strains were  examined in fixed cells from asynchronous or hydroxyurea-arrested cultures by immunofluorescence with anti-tubulin antibodies. Under these conditions, the microtubules of vik1Delta mutants are indistinguishable from those of  wild-type strains. As described previously, cik1Delta mutants  have very short spindles compared with wild-type strains  and have longer, more abundant cytoplasmic microtubules  (Page and Snyder, 1992). This phenotype is identical to  that reported for kar3Delta mutants (Meluh and Rose, 1990;  Saunders et al., 1997). cik1Delta vik1Delta double mutants display  microtubules with no significant difference in length or  number to those of cik1Delta mutants (data not shown). Therefore, if disruption of VIK1 results in defects in microtubule  structure, these defects are not detected under these conditions. Finally, consistent with the hypothesis that Cik1p  and Vik1p function in complexes with Kar3p, the growth  rate and microtubule phenotypes of kar3Delta, kar3Delta cik1Delta,  kar3Delta vik1Delta, and kar3Delta cik1Delta vik1Delta mutants are all very  similar (data not shown).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>42132</offset><text>Loss of Vik1p Function Suppresses the cin8-3 kip1Delta Mutant</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>42191</offset><text>One vegetative function of Kar3p may be to oppose the  action of two other S. cerevisiae KRPs, the redundant  Cin8p and Kip1p motors (Hoyt et al., 1992, 1993; Saunders  and Hoyt, 1992; Saunders et al., 1997b). This Kar3p function has been proposed primarily due to genetic interactions between mutations in the genes encoding these  KRPs. Disruption of Cin8p and Kip1p function, using the  conditional cin8-3 kip1Delta mutant, results in a temperature-sensitive growth defect at 35 C that is partially suppressed  by disruption of Kar3p function (Saunders and Hoyt, 1992;  Hoyt et al., 1993; see below). However, disruption of  CIK1, encoding a Kar3p KAP, does not suppress cin8-3  kip1Delta (Fig. 8; Page et al., 1994), suggesting that the Kar3p  activity that opposes Cin8p and Kip1p is independent of  Cik1p. </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>42999</offset><text>Since Vik1p was identified as a second KAP for Kar3p  during vegetative growth, we tested whether disruption of  Vik1p function could suppress the temperature-sensitive  growth defect of the cin8-3 kip1Delta mutant. VIK1, CIK1,  and KAR3 were deleted individually from the cin8-3 kip1Delta  strain, and the resulting mutants were examined for  growth defects at 23 and 35 C (Fig. 8). As demonstrated  previously, the cin8-3 kip1Delta kar3Delta mutant grows significantly better than the original cin8-3 kip1Delta mutant at the  restrictive temperature of 35 C (Saunders and Hoyt, 1992;  Hoyt et al., 1993). Likewise, disruption of VIK1 also partially suppresses the cin8-3 kip1Delta temperature-sensitive  growth defect, as the cin8-3 kip1Delta vik1Delta mutant grows at  35 C. Introduction of a CEN plasmid encoding VIK1 into  the cin8-3 kip1Delta vik1Delta mutant restores temperature sensitivity to levels identical to the cin8-3 kip1Delta mutant (data  not shown). In contrast, growth of the cin8-3 kip1Delta cik1Delta  mutant is significantly diminished at all temperatures compared with the cin8-3 kip1Delta mutant, suggesting a possible  added defect in the triple mutant. Therefore, like Kar3p,  Vik1p functions antagonistically to Cin8p and Kip1p. This  result further indicates that Cik1p and Vik1p are involved  in distinct Kar3p functions.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>44312</offset><text>Discussion</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>44323</offset><text>Cik1p is a previously described kinesin-associated protein  that interacts with the yeast KRP Kar3p (Page and Snyder,  1992; Page et al., 1994). We have characterized a Cik1p-homologous protein called Vik1p that is present in vegetatively growing cells but, unlike Cik1p, is not detected in  mating-pheromone treated cells. Coimmunoprecipitation  experiments demonstrate that Vik1p also physically associates with Kar3p and that the Kar3p-Vik1p complex is  separate from that of Kar3p and Cik1p. Therefore, Kar3p  interacts with two different KAPs to form distinct complexes within the same cell.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>44920</offset><text>Kar3p and Vik1p Are Interdependent for Proper  Localization to the SPBs of Vegetatively Growing Cells</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>45022</offset><text>Vik1p requires Kar3p function for its SPB localization.  This suggests that Kar3p-Vik1p complex formation and,  presumably, the minus-end directed microtubule-motor  activity of Kar3p are required to deliver Vik1p to the SPB.  In the absence of Kar3p, Vik1p mislocalizes to cytoplasmic  patches and is excluded from the nucleus. In contrast,  Cik1p mislocalizes throughout the nucleus in the absence  of Kar3p during vegetative growth (Page et al., 1994). Two  possible models for Vik1p localization can be invoked.  First, Vik1p may require association with Kar3p for its nuclear import. In support of this idea, Vik1p does not have  sequences predicting a nuclear localization signal. Moreover, Kar3p can target to the nucleus independent of both  Cik1p and Vik1p (Page et al., 1994; this study). This nuclear import of Vik1p by association with Kar3p would be  analogous to the nuclear import of the yeast gamma-tubulin  complex. The import of this complex, and its subsequent  binding to the nuclear face of the SPB, requires the nuclear localization signal of one of its components, Spc98p  (Pereira et al., 1998). Alternatively, the Kar3p-Vik1p complex may be associated primarily with the cytoplasmic face  of the SPB. Therefore, absence of Kar3p would result in  release of Vik1p to the cytoplasm specifically, as observed.  At this point, we cannot distinguish between these two  possibilities, but future studies will address whether the  Kar3p-Vik1p complex is on the nuclear, cytoplasmic, or  both faces of the SPB.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>46547</offset><text>We demonstrate that, whereas Cik1p is required to localize Kar3p to the SPBs and cytoplasmic microtubules of  mating pheromone-treated cells (Page et al., 1994), Vik1p  is required for proper concentration of Kar3p at the SPBs  of vegetatively growing cells. In the absence of Vik1p,  Kar3p mislocalizes to nuclear patches, and can be seen  along spindle microtubules in many cells. Therefore, Vik1p  is required for proper targeting and/or maintenance of  Kar3p at the SPB. Vik1p might mediate interactions between Kar3p and other proteins that tether the complex  to the SPB. Alternatively, Vik1p could prevent release of  Kar3p from the minus-ends of microtubules, where its motor activity would cause it to accumulate.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>47270</offset><text>In the absence of both Cik1p and Vik1p, Kar3p again  mislocalizes but is more diffuse throughout the nucleus.  This suggests that Cik1p may be partially redundant with  Vik1p for targeting Kar3p to the SPB. However, Cik1p's  primary vegetative function may be to direct localization  of Kar3p to other sites within the nucleus, such as nuclear  patches and the spindle. This is supported by the observation that the faint nuclear patch staining of Kar3p seen in  wild-type cells is diminished in cik1Delta cells. Detection of  Kar3p at these sites is greatly enhanced in the absence of  its Vik1p-mediated SPB localization.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>47891</offset><text>Finally, since some residual SPB staining can be detected in a small percentage of cik1Delta vik1Delta cells, Kar3p  may have an inherent KAP-independent ability to localize  to the SPB. This localization is likely to depend on its minus-end directed microtubule motor domain, rather than  its non-motor stalk and tail domains. These latter regions  of Kar3p have been shown previously to be sufficient for  its spindle and SPB localization (Meluh and Rose, 1990;  Page et al., 1994). Cik1p and Vik1p presumably target  Kar3p to various sites of action through interactions with  its nonmotor domain.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>48486</offset><text>Kar3p Forms Three Functionally Distinct Complexes  during the Yeast Life Cycle</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>48565</offset><text>Phenotypic, genetic, and biochemical analysis of Kar3p, by  several different groups (Meluh and Rose, 1990; Roof et al.,  1991; Saunders and Hoyt, 1992; Hoyt et al., 1993; Endow  et al., 1994; Middleton and Carbon, 1994; Cottingham and  Hoyt, 1997; DeZwaan et al., 1997; Saunders et al., 1997a;  Huyett et al., 1998), has strongly suggested that Kar3p is a  multifunctional KRP. An intriguing question in the study  of molecular motors is how can one motor protein perform several different functions within a single cell.Our  results indicate that Kar3p interacts with two related proteins to form three complexes that are involved in distinct  microtubule-mediated cellular processes. We believe that  the ability of Kar3p to interact with these associated proteins is crucial to its functional versatility. The exact molecular functions of each of these Kar3p complexes are yet  to be defined. However, based on phenotypic and genetic  analysis, as well as localization studies, our data reveal  some possible general roles for the Kar3p-Cik1p complex  during mating and the Kar3p-Cik1p and Kar3p-Vik1p complexes during mitosis (Fig. 9). </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>49707</offset><text>The best defined of Kar3p's functions is its role in the  nuclear congression step of karyogamy, during which it associates with Cik1p (Meluh and Rose, 1990; Page et al.,  1994). This complex localizes to cytoplasmic microtubules  even in the absence of the Kar3p motor domain (Meluh  and Rose, 1990; Page and Snyder, 1992; Page et al., 1994),  indicating that the nonmotor region of the complex also  has microtubule-binding capacity. In the absence of either  of these two proteins, microtubules from the SPBs of opposing mating partners fail to interdigitate (Meluh and  Rose, 1990; Page et al., 1994). Together, these results suggest a model in which the Kar3p-Cik1p complex acts as a  cross-linker between antiparallel microtubules emanating  from the SPBs of mating partners. The minus-end directed  microtubule-motor activity of Kar3p can then create the  force that pulls the nuclei together by sliding cross-linked  microtubules past one another (Fig. 9 A).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>50674</offset><text>Despite many studies on the function of Kar3p during  vegetative growth, its role during mitosis remains obscure.  Our identification of two Kar3p-interacting proteins with  distinct Kar3p-related vegetative phenotypes should help  elucidate the exact mitotic functions of this KRP. Disruption of either KAR3 or CIK1 results in similar mitotic phenotypes, including very short spindles indicative of a spindle assembly defect (Meluh and Rose, 1990; Page and  Snyder, 1992; Saunders et al., 1997a) and a mitotic delay  mediated by the spindle-assembly checkpoint (Roof et al.,  1991; Manning, B.D., J.A. Wallace, and M. Snyder, unpublished observation). Unlike during mating, the Kar3p-Cik1p complex is in the nucleus during the mitotic cell  cycle, where it associates with the SPBs and, to a lesser extent, spindle microtubules (Page and Snyder, 1992; Page  et al., 1994; Saunders et al., 1997a). Analogous to its role in  karyogamy, the complex may act within the spindle to  cross-link and slide antiparallel microtubules from opposing SPBs past one another, thereby creating an inward  force on the spindle (Fig. 9 B). This force may generate a  tension important for proper spindle assembly. Alternatively, the Kar3p-Cik1p microtubule cross-linking activity  could be crucial to the organization of a bipolar spindle.  This spindle assembly defect would account for the chromosome instability phenotype of cik1Delta mutants (Page and  Snyder, 1992). Additionally, it is possible that this complex  could play a more direct role in chromosome segregation,  perhaps as a kinetochore motor (Hyman et al., 1992; Middleton and Carbon, 1994).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>52313</offset><text>Kar3p is likely to have a separate mitotic function that  is mediated by interaction with Vik1p at the SPBs. The  benomyl resistance phenotype of vik1Delta mutants, suggests  that the Kar3p-Vik1p complex may be involved in microtubule depolymerization (Fig. 9 C). The motor domain of  Kar3p has been shown to possess minus-end-specific microtubule-depolymerizing activity in vitro (Endow et al.,  1994), and has been suggested by phenotypic analysis to  depolymerize microtubules in vivo (Saunders et al., 1997).  Kar3p complexed with Vik1p, specifically, might possess  this activity. Alternatively, Kar3p may require interaction  with Vik1p to prevent release from microtubule minus  ends where it catalyzes microtubule depolymerization. At  this point, it is unclear whether this complex acts on cytoplasmic microtubules, the spindle, or both. Disruption of  VIK1 does not result in any detectable differences in the  microtubule structures of fixed cells compared with wild-type strains. It is possible that accumulation of Kar3p on  the spindle, observed in vik1Delta mutants, could stabilize  these microtubules and account for the benomyl resistance  phenotype.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>53478</offset><text>Based on genetic analysis, Kar3p-Vik1p function is detrimental to mutants lacking the plus-end-directed Cin8p  and Kip1p KRPs. These proteins are members of the  BimC family of KRPs and are believed to act as homotetrameric bipolar motor proteins that generate a SPB separating force during spindle assembly and anaphase B  (Hoyt et al., 1992; Saunders et al., 1995; Kashina et al.,  1997; Straight et al., 1998). Disruption of either KAR3 or  VIK1 can suppress the temperature-sensitive growth defect of the cin8-3 kip1Delta mutant, suggesting that the Kar3p-Vik1p complex may oppose the function of Cin8p and  Kip1p (Fig. 9 C; Saunders and Hoyt, 1992; Hoyt et al.,  1993). Interestingly, a TUB2 mutation that stablilizes microtubules can also suppress this mutant (Saunders et al.,  1997a), suggesting that a defect in the putative microtubule depolymerizing activity of the Kar3p-Vik1p complex  could be sufficient for suppression of cin8-3 kip1Delta.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>54429</offset><text>The functional interactions between the two vegetative  Kar3p complexes may be complicated. For example, disruption of VIK1 partially suppresses the temperature-sensitive growth defect and mitotic delay of cik1Delta mutants.  One interpretation of this result is that the two Kar3p  complexes partially oppose one another. It is also interesting to note that cik1Delta mutants, in which Kar3p's SPB localization is unperturbed, have much stronger phenotypes  (Page and Snyder, 1992) than those of vik1Delta mutants, in  which Kar3p is no longer concentrated at the SPBs. Therefore, the most critical of Kar3p functions during vegetative  growth may occur at sites other than the spindle poles. Future studies will address these issues, but it is clear from  our current study that Cik1p and Vik1p are not functionally redundant.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>55249</offset><text>KRP Regulation and Targeting by Kinesin-associated Proteins</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>55309</offset><text>In general, the functional specificity of KRPs is determined by their nonmotor domains. Some KRPs can target  to their sites of action independent of associated proteins.  For example, the Drosophila Nod protein, involved in chromosome movements during mitosis, contains a DNA binding motif in its nonmotor domain (Afshar et al., 1995).  However, the targeting of many KRPs will likely be mediated through complex formation with nonmotor subunits  (i.e., KAPs). The highly divergent nature of the nonmotor  domains of KRPs (reviewed by Goldstein, 1993; Vale  and Fletterick, 1997) suggest that interacting proteins will  also be diverse in sequence. Nevertheless, we expect that  mechanisms of motor targeting by KAPs will exist that are  universal.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>56059</offset><text>The light chains of conventional kinesin are the most  studied of all KAPs. Several different KLCs can exist  within a single cell (Cyr et al., 1991; Beushausen et al.,  1993; Wedaman et al., 1993; Rahman et al., 1998), and  these are thought to control the cargo-binding specificity  of KHCs (Khodjakov et al., 1998; Liao and Gundersen,  1998). Therefore, it is possible that different KLCs target  kinesin to distinct membranous organelles and vesicles,  and it has been suggested that KLC mediates the interaction between kinesin and membranes (Stenoien and Brady,  1997). Additionally, KLCs might regulate KHC-microtubule binding and/or motor activity by contacting the motor  domain when kinesin is in a folded confirmation (Hackney  et al., 1992; Verhey et al., 1998).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>56834</offset><text>Little is known about the regulation and targeting of  specific KRPs. The tail domain of the Xenopus mitotic  KRP, Xklp2, has recently been shown to require cytoplasmic dynein and a microtubule-associated protein, TPX2,  to localize to spindle poles (Wittmann et al., 1998). However, these proteins are not tightly associated KAPs. Our  results demonstrate that Kar3p localization is regulated  through its interaction with two different KAPs, Cik1p  and Vik1p (Page et al., 1994; this study). These KAPs control various Kar3p functions, at least in part, by targeting  the motor to discrete sites within the cell. Whether Cik1p  and Vik1p modulate motor activity once Kar3p is at these  sites is not yet known. The study of these proteins should  define regulatory strategies used by other KRPs and help  elucidate general elements underlying the functional diversity of KRPs.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>57712</offset><text>Figures and Tables</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>57731</offset><text>Strain List </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">table</infon><offset>57744</offset><text>   Strain  Genotype   Y270  MATa/MATalpha ura3-52/ura3-52 lys2-801/lys2-801 ade2-101/ade2-101 trp1-Delta1/trp1-Delta1 his3-Delta200/his3-Delta200  Y817  MATa ura3-52 ade2-101 leu2-3,112 his3-Delta200 cin8-3 kip1Delta::HIS3  Y818  MATalpha ura3-52 ade2-101 leu2-3,112 his3-Delta200 cin8-3 kip1Delta::HIS3  Y1707  MATalpha ura3-52 lys2-801 ade2-101 trp1-Delta1 his3-Delta200 cik1Delta::TRP1  Y1731  MATa ura3-52 lys2-801 ade2-101 leu2-98 trp1-Delta1 his3-Delta200  Y1733  MATa/MATalpha ura3-52/ura3-52 lys2-801/lys2-801 ade2-101/ade2-101 trp1-Delta1/trp1-Delta1 his3-Delta200/his3-Delta200 vik1Delta::HIS3-Kmr/VIK1  Y1734*  MATa ura3-52 lys2-801 ade2-101 trp1-Delta1 his3-Delta200 vik1Delta::HIS3-Kmr  Y1738   MATa/MATalpha ura3-52/ura3-52 lys2-801/lys2-801 ade2-101/ade2-101 trp1-Delta1/trp1-Delta1 his3-Delta200/his3-Delta200 vik1Delta::HIS3-Kmr/VIK1  cik1-Delta3::TRP1/CIK1  Y1744  MATa ura3-52 lys2-801 ade2-101 leu2-98 trp1-Delta1 his3-Delta200 VIK1::3XHA  Y1745  MATa ura3-52 lys2-801 ade2-101 leu2-98 trp1-Delta1 his3-Delta200 cik1-Delta3::LEU2 VIK1::3XHA  Y1748  MATalpha ura3-52 ade2-101 leu2-3,112 his3-Delta200 cin8-3 kip1Delta::HIS3 vik1Delta::URA3-Kmr  Y1750  MATa ura3-52 lys2-801 ade2-101 leu2-98 trp1-Delta1 his3-Delta200 kar3-Delta4::URA3 VIK1::3XHA  Y1751   MATalpha ura3-52 leu2-98 his3-Delta200 cik1Delta::LEU2 KAR3::HAT  Y1752  MATa ura3-52 leu2-98 his3-Delta200 canr vik1Delta::HIS3-Kmr KAR3::HAT  Y1753||  MATa/MATalpha ura3-52/ura3-52 leu2-98/leu2-98 his3-Delta200/his3-Delta200 vik1Delta::HIS3-Kmr/VIK1 cik1Delta::LEU2/CIK1 KAR3::HAT/KAR3::HAT  Y1758  MATa ura3-52 ade2-101 leu2-3,112 his3-Delta200 cin8-3 kip1Delta::HIS3 cik1-Delta3::LEU2  Y1759  MATalpha ura3-52 ade2-101 leu2-3,112 his3-Delta200 cin8-3 kip1Delta::HIS3 kar3-Delta4::URA3  Y1864  MATalpha ura3-52 leu2-98 trp1-Delta1 cik1Delta::LEU2  Y1869  MATa ura3-52 leu2-98 his3-Delta200 canr plus pB227  Y1870  MATa ura3-52 leu2-98 his3-Delta200 canr KAR3::HAT  Y1871   MATa/MATalpha ura3-52/ura3-52 leu2-98/leu2-98 his3-Delta200/his3-Delta200 cik1Delta::LEU2/CIK1 KAR3::HAT/KAR3</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>59601</offset><text> Y1733 segregant.   </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>59625</offset><text> Y1707 x Y1734.   </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>59648</offset><text> Y1871 segregant.   </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>59672</offset><text> Y1751 x Y1752.   </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>59695</offset><text> Y1864 x Y1870.   </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>59718</offset><text>Vik1p is a homologue of Cik1p. (A) Schematic representation of  Cik1p and Vik1p. Regions  with the same shading pattern between the two proteins share at least 25%  amino acid sequence identity. The two proteins have  homologous regions predicted to form alpha-helical  coiled-coil structures (wavy  line shading), as well as two  other stretches of homology  in their carboxyl termini  (horizonal and vertical line  shading). Cik1p contains a  nuclear localization signal at  its NH2 terminus (black box).  (B) Amino acid sequence  alignment of Vik1p and  Cik1p. Identical and similar  residues are indicated by  dark and light shading, respectively. The predicted  coiled-coil regions of the two  proteins are denoted by a  black bar over the sequence,  whereas the nuclear localization signal of Cik1p is underlined. The alignment was  performed with BCM Search  Launcher: Multiple Sequence Alignments (Baylor  College of Medicine, Houston, TX). Shading was performed by the Boxshade 3.21  program (ISREC Bioinformatics Group).</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>60746</offset><text>Vik1p is not present in mating pheromone-treated cells  and does not coimmunoprecipitate with Cik1p. Cell lysates were  prepared from a VIK1::3XHA strain (Y1744) and a VIK1 untagged strain (Y1731) that were either grown vegetatively (alpha-F -)  or first exposed to the alpha-factor mating pheromone (alpha-F +). Proteins from these lysates were either separated by SDS-PAGE using a 10% gel (Lysate) or first immunoprecipitated with anti-HA  antibodies (HA IP) or anti-Cik1p antibodies (Cik1 IP) before  SDS-PAGE separation. (A) Immunoblot analysis with anti-HA  antibodies detects a protein of 92 kD in VIK1::3XHA cell lysates  and anti-HA immunoprecipitations from vegetative cells, but not  from alpha-factor treated cells, anti-Cik1p immunoprecipitations, or  VIK1 anti-HA immunoprecipitations. (B) Immunoblot analysis  with anti-Cik1p antibodies detects the 73-77-kD Cik1 protein in  VIK1::3XHA cell lysates and anti-Cik1p immunoprecipitations  from both vegetative and alpha-factor treated cells, but not from  VIK1::3XHA or VIK1 anti-HA immunoprecipitations. The mass  of molecular mass markers are shown in kilodaltons.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>61863</offset><text>Vik1p coimmunoprecipitates with Kar3p. Cell lysates  were prepared from vegetatively growing cultures of a wild-type  (WT) VIK1 untagged strain (Y1731; HA-tag -) and wild-type  (Y1744), kar3Delta (Y1750), and cik1Delta (Y1745) VIK1::3XHA strains  (HA-tag +). Proteins from these lysates were either separated by  SDS-PAGE using an 8% gel (A; Lysates) or first immunoprecipitated with anti-Kar3p antibodies (B; alpha-Kar3p IPs) before SDS-PAGE separation. (A) Immunoblot analysis with anti-HA antibodies detects the 92 kD Vik1-3XHA protein in cell lysates from  the wild-type, kar3Delta, and cik1Delta VIK1::3XHA strains, but not  from the VIK1 untagged strain. (B, top) Immunoblot analysis  with anti-HA antibodies detects Vik1p-3XHA in anti-Kar3p immunoprecipitations from the wild-type and cik1Delta VIK1::3XHA  strains, but not from the VIK1 untagged strain or the kar3Delta  VIK1::3XHA strain (B, bottom). Immunoblot analysis with anti-Kar3p antibodies detects the 88 kD Kar3 protein in anti-Kar3p  immunoprecipitations from the wild-type VIK1 untagged strain  and wild-type and cik1Delta VIK1::3XHA strains, but not from the  kar3Delta VIK1::3XHA strain (B, bottom). The mass of molecular  mass markers are shown in kilodaltons.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>63072</offset><text>Vik1p localizes to  the spindle-pole bodies. Cells  from growing cultures of  VIK1 untagged strain Y1731  (A) and VIK1::3XHA strain  Y1744 (B) were prepared for  indirect immunofluorescence  microscopy using anti-HA  antibodies (A-C, left), anti-Tub2p antibodies (A and B,  middle), and Hoechst 33258  staining (A-C, right). Representative cells are pictured:  (A) two cells with preanaphase spindles from the VIK1  untagged strain demonstrating background staining; (B)  two cells with preanaphase  spindles from the VIK1::3XHA  strain displaying Vik1p-3XHA  staining at the spindle poles;  (C) a field of VIK1::3XHA  cells from a preparation not  stained with anti-Tub2p antibodies, demonstrating that  Vik1p-3XHA localization to  one or two dots at the nuclear  periphery does not depend on  costaining of microtubules. Presumptive spindle-pole staining of two preanaphase cells  and one cell in anaphase (inset) is indicated (C, arrowheads). The portion of the  nucleus that has entered the  bud in the inset C cell is out  of the plane of focus, but its  periphery overlaps with the  dot indicated by the arrowhead.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>64197</offset><text>The spindle-pole  body localization of Vik1p  depends on Kar3p. Cells  from growing cultures of a  kar3Delta VIK1 untagged strain  (A), kar3Delta VIK1::3XHA  strain Y1750 (B), Y1750 containing KAR3 on a YCp50-derived CEN plasmid (C),  and cik1Delta VIK1::3XHA strain  Y1745 (D) were prepared for  indirect immunofluorescence  microscopy with anti-HA antibodies (left), anti-Tub2p  antibodies (middle), and  Hoechst 33258 staining  (right). Representative preanaphase cells are pictured:  (A) an untagged cell demonstrating background staining; (B) a cell displaying  Vik1p-3XHA mislocalization  to cytoplasmic patches in the  absence of Kar3p; (C) restoration of Vik1p-3XHA spindle-pole localization by introduction of a wild-type  copy of KAR3, and; (D)  Vik1p-3XHA localization to  the poles of a short spindle  from a cik1Delta cell.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>65022</offset><text>Concentrated localization of Kar3p to the  spindle-pole bodies depends  on Vik1p. Cells from growing cultures of KAR3 untagged strain Y1869 (A) and  Kar3::HAT haploid segregants from strain Y1753  (B-E) were prepared for indirect immunofluorescence  microscopy with anti-HA antibodies (left), anti-Tub2p  antibodies (middle), and  Hoechst 33258 staining  (right). Representative preanaphase cells are pictured:  (A) an untagged cell demonstrating background staining; (B) a wild-type cell with  Kar3p-HAT staining primarily at the spindle poles, as  well as faint patches confined  to the nucleus (as determined  by overlapping Hoechst staining); (C) a cik1Delta cell with  Kar3p-HAT remaining at the  spindle-poles, the nuclear  patch staining is diminished  in these cells; (D) a vik1Delta  cell with Kar3p-HAT mislocalized to spindle microtubules and bright nuclear  patches, and; (E) a cik1Delta  vik1Delta cell with Kar3p-HAT mislocalized to bright  patches more diffusely distributed throughout the nucleus.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>66026</offset><text>Quantitation of Kar3p Localization in Preanaphase Cells </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">table</infon><offset>66083</offset><text>     % Kar3p-HAT localization              Strain    N   WT  100   0   0   0  200  cik1Delta  100    0   0   0  200  vik1Delta    0  44  22  34  172  cik1Delta vik1Delta    0  84   9   7  174</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>66276</offset><text>Anti-HA staining of asynchronous cells from isogenic Y1753 haploid segregants was  used to quantitate Kar3p-HAT localization in preanaphase cells by immunoflorescence. Four different localization patterns were observed:   </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>66500</offset><text> Bright SPB staining with faint nuclear patches.   </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>66555</offset><text> Bright nuclear patch staining.   </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>66593</offset><text> Bright nuclear patches and faint SPB staining.   </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>66647</offset><text> Bright nuclear patches and spindle-microtubule staining.   </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>66711</offset><text> Nuclear patch staining was diminished in cik1Delta cells.           </text></passage><passage><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>66781</offset><text>Phenotypic analysis of isogenic wild-type,  cik1Delta, vik1Delta, and cik1Delta  vik1Delta strains. Isogenic haploid segregants from a tetratype tetrad of the cik1Delta/ CIK1 vik1Delta/VIK1 double  heterozygous diploid strain  Y1738 were grown overnight  to stationary phase. 10-fold  serial dilutions with a starting  concentration of 1 x 106  cells/ml were spotted in 5 mul  drops onto agar plates containing either rich medium  (A and B) or rich medium  with 10 mug/ml benomyl (C).  Plates were incubated for  four days at either 23 C (A  and C) or 37 C (B). (A)  Growth on rich medium at  23 C was similar for all four  strains. (B) Wild-type and  vik1Delta growth is indistinguishable at 37 C, whereas  cik1Delta growth is temperature  sensitive. The cik1Delta vik1Delta  double mutant grows better  at the elevated temperature  than cik1Delta mutants. (C)  Compared with growth of  the wild-type strain on  benomyl, the vik1Delta mutant is more benomyl resistant, and the  cik1Delta and cik1Delta vik1Delta mutants are more benomyl sensitive. (D)  Cells from mid-logarithmically growing cultures of wild-type,  cik1Delta, vik1Delta, and cik1Delta vik1Delta haploid segregants of Y1738 were  stained with Hoechst 33258 and large budded cells with a single  preanaphase nucleus were counted. The percentage of these cells  present in the total population counted is shown. The results represent the average of two experiments in each of which greater  than 300 total cells were counted for each strain.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>68236</offset><text>The temperature-sensitive growth defect of the  cin8-3 kip1Delta mutant is suppressed by disruption of  KAR3 or VIK1, but not  CIK1. Overnight cultures  were grown to stationary  phase, diluted down to 5 x  106 cells/ml, and 5-mul spots  were plated to rich medium  then incubated for three days  at 23 or 35 C. Pictured are  wild-type strain Y1731 and  cin8-3 kip1Delta mutant strains  Y818, vik1Delta Y1748, cik1Delta  Y1758, and kar3Delta Y1759.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>68672</offset><text>Schematic representation of possible functions for  Kar3p complexes during the yeast life cycle. Motors and motor  complexes are shown as described in the figure legend. The kinesin-related motor domains of these proteins are represented by  circles, and the directionality of the motor is indicated by an arrow. The area within the nucleus is indicated by gray shading,  whereas SPBs and associated microtubules are represented by  the striped regions on the periphery of the nucleus and the heavy  lines emanating from these region, respectively. (A) During mating, Kar3p associates with Cik1p which holds the motor in the cytoplasm in response to pheromone. After cell fusion, the Kar3p-Cik1p complex is responsible for the nuclear congression step of  karyogamy. This is accomplished by cross-linking and sliding  antiparallel microtubules from opposing SPBs past one another,  thereby pulling the MATa and MATalpha nuclei together. (B) Kar3p  interacts with Cik1p during vegetative growth as well. The  Kar3p-Cik1p complex is in the nucleus during mitosis, where it  may again act as a cross-linking/sliding motor. In this model,  Kar3p-Cik1p would exert an inwardly directed force on the mitotic spindle. This force may create a tension required for proper  spindle assembly and chromosome segregation since both cik1  and kar3 mutants have strong defects in these processes. (C)  Kar3p also interacts with Vik1p during vegetative growth. The  Kar3p-Vik1p complex functions primarily at the SPBs, either on  the cytoplasmic face, the nuclear face, or both. Based on phenotypic and genetic analysis, this complex may have microtubule-depolymerizing activity that opposes the SPB separating force  generated by Cin8p and Kip1p.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>70401</offset><text>Abbreviations used in this paper</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>70434</offset><text>HA</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>70437</offset><text>hemagglutinin</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>70451</offset><text>HAT</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>70455</offset><text>HA/transposon tag</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>70473</offset><text>KAP</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>70477</offset><text>kinesin-associated protein</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>70504</offset><text>KHC</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>70508</offset><text>kinesin-heavy chain</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>70528</offset><text>KLC</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>70532</offset><text>kinesin light chain</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>70552</offset><text>KRP</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>70556</offset><text>kinesin-related protein</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>70580</offset><text>ORF</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>70584</offset><text>open reading frame</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>70603</offset><text>SPB</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>70607</offset><text>spindle-pole bodies</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>70627</offset><text>References</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">833</infon><infon key="lpage">843</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Afshar;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Scholey;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Hawley;given-names:RS</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">7490288</infon><infon key="source">J Cell  Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">131</infon><infon key="year">1995</infon><offset>70638</offset><text>Identification of the chromosome localization domain of the DrosophilaNod kinesin-like protein</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1265</infon><infon key="lpage">1270</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Arnal;given-names:I</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Metoz;given-names:F</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:DeBonis;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wade;given-names:RH</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8939577</infon><infon key="source">Curr Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">6</infon><infon key="year">1996</infon><offset>70733</offset><text>Three-dimensional structure of functional motor proteins on microtubules</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">459</infon><infon key="lpage">467</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bascom-Slack;given-names:CA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dawson;given-names:DS</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9334348</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">139</infon><infon key="year">1997</infon><offset>70806</offset><text>The yeast motor protein, Kar3p, is essential for meiosis I</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">901</infon><infon key="lpage">909</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Beushausen;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kladakis;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Jaffe;given-names:H</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8274223</infon><infon key="source">DNA Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">12</infon><infon key="year">1993</infon><offset>70865</offset><text>Kinesin light chains: identification and characterization of a family of proteins from the optic lobe of the  squid Loligo pealii. </text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">461</infon><infon key="lpage">468</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bond;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fridovich-Keil;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Pillus;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Mulligan;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Solomon;given-names:F</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">3753663</infon><infon key="source">Cell</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">44</infon><infon key="year">1986</infon><offset>70997</offset><text>A  chicken-yeast chimeric beta-tubulin protein is incorporated into mouse microtubules in vivo. </text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1087</infon><infon key="lpage">1105</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Burns;given-names:N</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Grimwade;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ross-Macdonald;given-names:PB</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Choi;given-names:E-Y</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Finberg;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Roeder;given-names:GS</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Snyder;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">7926789</infon><infon key="source">Genes Dev</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">8</infon><infon key="year">1994</infon><offset>71094</offset><text>Large-scale characterization of gene expression, protein localization and gene disruption in Saccharomyces cerevisiae.  </text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">268</infon><infon key="lpage">270</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Cole;given-names:DG</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Chinn;given-names:SW</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wedaman;given-names:KP</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Hall;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Vuong;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Scholey;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8232586</infon><infon key="source">Nature</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">366</infon><infon key="year">1993</infon><offset>71215</offset><text>Novel heterotrimeric kinesin-related protein purified form sea urchin eggs</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">993</infon><infon key="lpage">1008</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Cole;given-names:DG</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Diener;given-names:DR</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Himelblau;given-names:AL</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Beech;given-names:PL</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Fuster;given-names:JC</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Rosenbaum;given-names:JL</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9585417</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">141</infon><infon key="year">1998</infon><offset>71290</offset><text>Chlamydomonas kinesin-II-dependent intraflagellar  transport (IFT): IFT particles contain proteins required for ciliary assembly  in Caenorhabditis eleganssensory neurons</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1041</infon><infon key="lpage">1053</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Cottingham;given-names:FR</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hoyt;given-names:MA</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9281582</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">138</infon><infon key="year">1997</infon><offset>71463</offset><text>Mitotic spindle positioning in Saccharomyces cerevisiaeis accomplished by antagonistically acting microtubule motor proteins</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">10114</infon><infon key="lpage">10118</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Cyr;given-names:JL</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Pfister;given-names:KK</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Bloom;given-names:GS</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Slaughter;given-names:CA</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Brady;given-names:ST</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">1946431</infon><infon key="source">Proc Natl Acad Sci USA</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">88</infon><infon key="year">1991</infon><offset>71588</offset><text>Molecular genetics of kinesin light chains: generation of isoforms by alternative splicing</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1023</infon><infon key="lpage">1040</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:DeZwaan;given-names:TM</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ellingson;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Pellman;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Roof;given-names:DM</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9281581</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">138</infon><infon key="year">1997</infon><offset>71679</offset><text>Kinesin-related KIP3 of Saccharomyces cerevisiaeis required for a distinct step in nuclear migration</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">303</infon><infon key="lpage">312</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Elledge;given-names:SJ</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Davis;given-names:RW</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">3063604</infon><infon key="source">Gene</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">70</infon><infon key="year">1988</infon><offset>71780</offset><text>A family of versatile centromeric vectors  designed for use in the sectoring-shuffle mutagenesis assay in Saccharomyces cerevisiae. </text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2708</infon><infon key="lpage">2713</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Endow;given-names:SA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kang;given-names:SJ</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Satterwhite;given-names:LL</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Rose;given-names:MD</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Skeen;given-names:VP</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Salmon;given-names:ED</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">7912193</infon><infon key="source">EMBO (Eur Mol  Biol Organ) J</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">1994</infon><offset>71913</offset><text>Yeast Kar3 is a minus-end microtubule motor protein that destabilizes microtubules preferentially at the minus ends</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">13657</infon><infon key="lpage">13666</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Gauger;given-names:AK</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Goldstein;given-names:LSB</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8514798</infon><infon key="source">J Biol Chem</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">268</infon><infon key="year">1993</infon><offset>72029</offset><text>The Drosophilakinesin light chain</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1451</infon><infon key="lpage">1464</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Gehrung;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Snyder;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">2211820</infon><infon key="source">J  Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">111</infon><infon key="year">1990</infon><offset>72063</offset><text>The SPA2 gene of Saccharomyces cerevisiaeis important for pheromone-induced morphogenesis and efficient mating</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">319</infon><infon key="lpage">351</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Goldstein;given-names:LSB</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8122906</infon><infon key="source">Annu Rev Genet</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">27</infon><infon key="year">1993</infon><offset>72174</offset><text>With apologies to Scheherazade: tails of 1001 kinesin motors</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1769</infon><infon key="lpage">1776</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Gulick;given-names:AM</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Song;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Endow;given-names:SA</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Rayment;given-names:I</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9485302</infon><infon key="source">Biochemistry</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">37</infon><infon key="year">1998</infon><offset>72235</offset><text>X-ray crystal structure of the yeast Kar3 motor domain complexed with Mg.ADP to 2.3 A resolution</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">933</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Guthrie;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fink;given-names:GR</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">2005781</infon><infon key="source">Methods Enzymol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">194</infon><infon key="year">1991</infon><offset>72332</offset><text>Guide to yeast genetics and molecular biology</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">8696</infon><infon key="lpage">8701</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hackney;given-names:DD</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Levitt;given-names:JD</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Suhan;given-names:J</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">1569110</infon><infon key="source">J Biol Chem</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">267</infon><infon key="year">1992</infon><offset>72378</offset><text>Kinesin undergoes a 9 S to 6 S conformation transition</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">135</infon><infon key="lpage">141</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hirokawa;given-names:N</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">15157476</infon><infon key="source">Trends Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">6</infon><infon key="year">1996</infon><offset>72433</offset><text>Organelle transport along microtubules-the role of KIFs</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">519</infon><infon key="lpage">526</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hirokawa;given-names:N</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9438838</infon><infon key="source">Science</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">279</infon><infon key="year">1998</infon><offset>72489</offset><text>Kinesin and dynein superfamily proteins and the mechanism of organelle transport</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">277</infon><infon key="lpage">279</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hirose;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lockhart;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Cross;given-names:RA</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Amos;given-names:LA</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">7617042</infon><infon key="source">Nature</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">376</infon><infon key="year">1995</infon><offset>72570</offset><text>Nucleotide-dependent angular change in kinesin motor domain bound to tubulin</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">9539</infon><infon key="lpage">9544</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hirose;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lockhart;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Cross;given-names:RA</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Amos;given-names:LA</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8790366</infon><infon key="source">Proc Natl Acad Sci USA</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">93</infon><infon key="year">1996</infon><offset>72647</offset><text>Three-dimensional cryoelectron microscopy of dimeric kinesin and ncd motor domains on microtubules</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">109</infon><infon key="lpage">120</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hoyt;given-names:MA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:He;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Loo;given-names:KK</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Saunders;given-names:WS</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">1618897</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">118</infon><infon key="year">1992</infon><offset>72746</offset><text>Two Saccharomyces  cerevisiaekinesin-related gene products required for mitotic spindle assembly</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">35</infon><infon key="lpage">44</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hoyt;given-names:MA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:He;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Totis;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Saunders;given-names:WS</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8224825</infon><infon key="source">Genetics</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">135</infon><infon key="year">1993</infon><offset>72843</offset><text>Loss of function of Saccharomyces cerevisiae kinesin-related CIN8 and KIP1 is suppressed by  KAR3motor domain mutations</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">295</infon><infon key="lpage">301</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Huyett;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kahana;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Silver;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Zeng;given-names:X</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Saunders;given-names:WS</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9427678</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Sci</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">111</infon><infon key="year">1998</infon><offset>72963</offset><text>The Kar3p and Kip2p motors function antagonistically at the spindle poles to influence cytoplasmic microtubule numbers</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">533</infon><infon key="lpage">536</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hyman;given-names:AA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Middleton;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Centola;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Mitchison;given-names:TJ</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Carbon;given-names:J</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">1406970</infon><infon key="source">Nature</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">359</infon><infon key="year">1992</infon><offset>73082</offset><text>Microtubule-motor activity of a yeast centromere-binding protein complex</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">163</infon><infon key="lpage">168</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ito;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fukada;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Murata;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Kimura;given-names:A</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">6336730</infon><infon key="source">J Bacteriol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">153</infon><infon key="year">1983</infon><offset>73155</offset><text>Transformation of intact yeast cells with alkali cations</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">257</infon><infon key="lpage">271</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kashina;given-names:AS</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Rogers;given-names:GC</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Scholey;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9268050</infon><infon key="source">Biochim Biophys Acta</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">1357</infon><infon key="year">1997</infon><offset>73212</offset><text>The bimC family of kinesins: essential bipolar mitotic motors driving centrosome separation</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">333</infon><infon key="lpage">343</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Khodjakov;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lizunova;given-names:EM</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Minin;given-names:AA</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Koonce;given-names:MP</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Gyoeva;given-names:FK</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9450959</infon><infon key="source">Mol Biol Cell</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">1998</infon><offset>73304</offset><text>A specific light chain of kinesin associates with mitochondria in cultured cells</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">369</infon><infon key="lpage">377</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kronstad;given-names:JW</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Holly;given-names:JA</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:MacKay;given-names:VL</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">3301002</infon><infon key="source">Cell</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">50</infon><infon key="year">1987</infon><offset>73385</offset><text>A yeast operator overlaps an upstream activation site</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">550</infon><infon key="lpage">555</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kull;given-names:FJ</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sablin;given-names:EP</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lau;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Fletterick;given-names:RJ</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Vale;given-names:RD</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8606779</infon><infon key="source">Nature</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">380</infon><infon key="year">1996</infon><offset>73439</offset><text>Crystal structure of the kinesin motor domain reveals a structural similarity to myosin</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">3990</infon><infon key="lpage">4002</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kurihara;given-names:LJ</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Stewart;given-names:BG</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Gammie;given-names:AE</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Rose;given-names:MD</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8754797</infon><infon key="source">Mol Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">1996</infon><offset>73527</offset><text>Kar4p, a karyogamy-specific component of the yeast pheromone response pathway</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">680</infon><infon key="lpage">685</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Laemmli;given-names:UK</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">5432063</infon><infon key="source">Nature</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">227</infon><infon key="year">1970</infon><offset>73605</offset><text>Cleavage of structural proteins during the assembly of the head of bacteriophage T4</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">9797</infon><infon key="lpage">9803</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Liao;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Gundersen;given-names:GG</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9545318</infon><infon key="source">J Biol Chem</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">273</infon><infon key="year">1998</infon><offset>73689</offset><text>Kinesin is a candidate for cross-bridging microtubules and intermediate filaments</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">22929</infon><infon key="lpage">22933</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lindesmith;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:McIlvain;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Argon;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Sheetz;given-names:MP</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9312551</infon><infon key="source">J Biol  Chem</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">272</infon><infon key="year">1997</infon><offset>73771</offset><text>Phosphotransferases associated with the regulation of kinesin motor activity</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">513</infon><infon key="lpage">525</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lupas;given-names:A</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8743703</infon><infon key="source">Methods Enzymol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">266</infon><infon key="year">1996</infon><offset>73848</offset><text>Prediction and analysis of coiled-coil structures</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1162</infon><infon key="lpage">1164</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lupas;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dyke;given-names:MV</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Stock;given-names:J</infon><infon key="source">Science</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">252</infon><infon key="year">1991</infon><offset>73898</offset><text>Predicting coiled coils from protein sequences</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1829</infon><infon key="lpage">1844</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Manning;given-names:BD</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Padmanabha;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Snyder;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9348527</infon><infon key="source">Mol Biol Cell</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">8</infon><infon key="year">1997</infon><offset>73945</offset><text>The Rho-GEF Rom2p  localizes to sites of polarized cell growth and participates in cytoskeletal  functions in Saccharomyces cerevisiae. </text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">19176</infon><infon key="lpage">19182</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:McIlvain;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Burkhardt;given-names:JK</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Hamm-Alvarez;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Argon;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Sheetz;given-names:MP</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8034676</infon><infon key="source">J Biol Chem</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">269</infon><infon key="year">1994</infon><offset>74082</offset><text>Regulation of kinesin activity by phosphorylation of kinesin-associated proteins</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1029</infon><infon key="lpage">1941</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Meluh;given-names:PB</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Rose;given-names:MD</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">2138512</infon><infon key="source">Cell</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">60</infon><infon key="year">1990</infon><offset>74163</offset><text>KAR3, a kinesin-related gene required for yeast nuclear fusion</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">7212</infon><infon key="lpage">7216</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Middleton;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Carbon;given-names:J</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8041770</infon><infon key="source">Proc Natl Acad Sci USA</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">91</infon><infon key="year">1994</infon><offset>74226</offset><text>KAR3-encoded kinesin is a minus-end-directed motor that functions with centromere binding proteins (CBF3) on  an in vitroyeast kinetochore</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">207</infon><infon key="lpage">219</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Moore;given-names:JD</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Endow;given-names:SA</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8867735</infon><infon key="source">Bioessays</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">18</infon><infon key="year">1996</infon><offset>74365</offset><text>Kinesin proteins: a phylum of motors for microtubule-based motility</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1414</infon><infon key="lpage">1429</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Page;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Snyder;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">1644287</infon><infon key="source">Genes Dev</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">6</infon><infon key="year">1992</infon><offset>74433</offset><text>CIK1: a developmentally regulated spindle pole  body-associated protein important for microtubule functions in Saccharomyces cerevisiae. </text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">507</infon><infon key="lpage">519</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Page;given-names:BD</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Satterwhite;given-names:LL</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Rose;given-names:MD</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Snyder;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8106549</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">124</infon><infon key="year">1994</infon><offset>74571</offset><text>Localization of the KAR3 kinesin heavy chain-like protein requires the CIK1 interacting protein</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">775</infon><infon key="lpage">793</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Pereira;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Knop;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Schiebel;given-names:E</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9529377</infon><infon key="source">Mol Biol Cell</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">1998</infon><offset>74667</offset><text>Spc98p directs the yeast g-tubulin complex into the nucleus and is subject to cell cycle-dependent phosphorylation on the nuclear side of the spindle-pole body</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">565</infon><infon key="lpage">601</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Pringle;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Adams;given-names:AEM</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Drubin;given-names:DG</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Haarer;given-names:BK</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">2005809</infon><infon key="source">Methods Enzymol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">194</infon><infon key="year">1991</infon><offset>74827</offset><text>Immunofluorescence methods for yeast</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">15395</infon><infon key="lpage">15403</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Rahman;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Friedman;given-names:DS</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Goldstein;given-names:LSB</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9624122</infon><infon key="source">J Biol Chem</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">273</infon><infon key="year">1998</infon><offset>74864</offset><text>Two kinesin light chain genes in mice: identification and characterization of the encoded proteins</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">95</infon><infon key="lpage">108</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Roof;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Meluh;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Rose;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">1618910</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">118</infon><infon key="year">1992</infon><offset>74963</offset><text>Kinesin-related proteins required for assembly of the mitotic spindle</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">693</infon><infon key="lpage">703</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Roof;given-names:DM</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Meluh;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Rose;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">1819517</infon><infon key="source">Cold Spring Harbor Symp Quant Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">61</infon><infon key="year">1991</infon><offset>75033</offset><text>Multiple kinesin-related proteins in yeast mitosis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">190</infon><infon key="lpage">195</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ross-MacDonald;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sheehan;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Roeder;given-names:GS</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Snyder;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8990184</infon><infon key="source">Proc Natl Acad Sci USA</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">94</infon><infon key="year">1997</infon><offset>75084</offset><text>A multipurpose transposon system for analyzing protein production, localization,  and function in Saccharomyces cerevisiae. </text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">555</infon><infon key="lpage">559</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Sablin;given-names:EP</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kull;given-names:FJ</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Cooke;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Vale;given-names:RD</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Fletterick;given-names:RJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8606780</infon><infon key="source">Nature</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">380</infon><infon key="year">1996</infon><offset>75209</offset><text>Crystal structure of the motor domain of the kinesin-related motor ncd</text></passage><passage><infon key="citation">Sambrook, J., E.F. Fritsch, and T. Maniatis. 1989. Molecular Cloning: A Laboratory Manual. 2nd edition. Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press, Cold  Spring Harbor, NY.</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><offset>75280</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">451</infon><infon key="lpage">458</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Saunders;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hoyt;given-names:MA</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">1643659</infon><infon key="source">Cell</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">70</infon><infon key="year">1992</infon><offset>75281</offset><text>Kinesin-related proteins required for structural integrity of the mitotic spindle</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">617</infon><infon key="lpage">624</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Saunders;given-names:WS</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Koshland;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Eshel;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Gibbons;given-names:IR</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Hoyt;given-names:MA</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">7860634</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">128</infon><infon key="year">1995</infon><offset>75363</offset><text>Saccharomyces cerevisiaekinesin- and dynein-related proteins required for anaphase chromosome segregation</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">417</infon><infon key="lpage">431</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Saunders;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hornack;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lengyel;given-names:V</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Deng;given-names:C</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9128252</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">137</infon><infon key="year">1997a</infon><offset>75469</offset><text>The Saccharomyces cerevisiaekinesin-related motor Kar3p acts at preanaphase spindle poles to limit the number and length of cytoplasmic microtubules</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1025</infon><infon key="lpage">1033</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Saunders;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lengyel;given-names:V</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Hoyt;given-names:MA</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9201713</infon><infon key="source">Mol Biol Cell</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">8</infon><infon key="year">1997b</infon><offset>75618</offset><text>Mitotic spindle function in  Saccharomyces cerevisiaerequires a balance between different types of kinesin-related motors</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1548</infon><infon key="lpage">1552</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Schnapp;given-names:BJ</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Reese;given-names:TS</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">2466291</infon><infon key="source">Proc Natl Acad Sci USA</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">86</infon><infon key="year">1989</infon><offset>75740</offset><text>Dynein is the motor for retrograde axonal transport of organelles</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1265</infon><infon key="lpage">1274</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Schneider;given-names:BL</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Seufert;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Steiner;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Yang;given-names:QH</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Futcher;given-names:AB</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8553697</infon><infon key="source">Yeast</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">11</infon><infon key="year">1995</infon><offset>75806</offset><text>Use of PCR epitope tagging for protein tagging in Saccharomyces cerevisiae.  </text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">4</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Scholey;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8601599</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">133</infon><infon key="year">1996</infon><offset>75884</offset><text>Kinesin-II, a membrane traffic motor in axons, axonems, and spindles</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">19</infon><infon key="lpage">27</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Sikorski;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hieter;given-names:P</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">2659436</infon><infon key="source">Genetics</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">122</infon><infon key="year">1989</infon><offset>75953</offset><text>A system of shuttle vectors and yeast host  strains designed for efficient manipulation of DNA in Saccharomyces cerevisiae. </text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">237</infon><infon key="lpage">249</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Spencer;given-names:F</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Gerring;given-names:SL</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Connelly;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Hieter;given-names:P</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">2407610</infon><infon key="source">Genetics</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">124</infon><infon key="year">1990</infon><offset>76078</offset><text>Mitotic chromosome transmission fidelity mutants in Saccharomyces cerevisiae. </text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">675</infon><infon key="lpage">689</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Stenoien;given-names:DL</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Brady;given-names:ST</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9247647</infon><infon key="source">Mol Biol Cell</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">8</infon><infon key="year">1997</infon><offset>76157</offset><text>Immunochemical analysis of kinesin light chain function</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">266</infon><infon key="lpage">268</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Steuer;given-names:ER</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wordeman;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Schroer;given-names:TA</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Sheetz;given-names:MP</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">2139718</infon><infon key="source">Nature</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">345</infon><infon key="year">1990</infon><offset>76213</offset><text>Localization of cytoplasmic dynein to mitotic spindles and kinetochores</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">687</infon><infon key="lpage">694</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Straight;given-names:AF</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sedat;given-names:JW</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Murray;given-names:AW</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9813090</infon><infon key="source">J Cell  Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">143</infon><infon key="year">1998</infon><offset>76285</offset><text>Time-lapse microscopy reveals unique roles for kinesins during anaphase in budding yeast</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">745</infon><infon key="lpage">777</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Vale;given-names:RD</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fletterick;given-names:RJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9442886</infon><infon key="source">Annu  Rev Cell Dev Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">13</infon><infon key="year">1997</infon><offset>76374</offset><text>The design plan of kinesin motos</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">39</infon><infon key="lpage">50</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Vale;given-names:RD</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Reese;given-names:TS</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Sheetz;given-names:MP</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">3926325</infon><infon key="source">Cell</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">42</infon><infon key="year">1985</infon><offset>76407</offset><text>Identification of a novel force generating protein, kinesin, involved in microtubule-based motility</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1053</infon><infon key="lpage">1066</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Verhey;given-names:KJ</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lizotte;given-names:DL</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Abramson;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Barenboim;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Schnapp;given-names:BJ</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Rapoport;given-names:TA</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9817761</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">143</infon><infon key="year">1998</infon><offset>76507</offset><text>Light chain-dependent regulation of kinesin's interaction with microtubules</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">155</infon><infon key="lpage">158</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wedaman;given-names:KP</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Knight;given-names:AE</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Kendrick-Jones;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Scholey;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8496962</infon><infon key="source">J Mol Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">231</infon><infon key="year">1993</infon><offset>76583</offset><text>Sequences of sea urchin kinesin light chain isoforms</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">371</infon><infon key="lpage">380</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wedaman;given-names:KP</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Meyer;given-names:DW</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Rashid;given-names:DJ</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Cole;given-names:DG</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Scholey;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8636215</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">132</infon><infon key="year">1996</infon><offset>76636</offset><text>Sequence and submolecular localization of the 115-kD accessory subunit of  the heterotrimeric kinesin-II (KRP85/95) complex</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">673</infon><infon key="lpage">685</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wittmann;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Boleti;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Antony;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Karsenti;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Vernos;given-names:I</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9813089</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">143</infon><infon key="year">1998</infon><offset>76760</offset><text>Localization of the kinesin-like protein Xklp2 to spindle poles requires a leucine zipper, a microtubule-associated protein, and dynein</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">8443</infon><infon key="lpage">8448</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yamazaki;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Nakata;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Okada;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Hirokawa;given-names:N</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8710890</infon><infon key="source">Proc Natl Acad Sci USA</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">93</infon><infon key="year">1996</infon><offset>76896</offset><text>Cloning and characterization of KAP3: a novel kinesin superfamily-associated protein of KIF3A/3B</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">879</infon><infon key="lpage">889</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yang;given-names:JT</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Laymon;given-names:RA</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Goldstein;given-names:LSB</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">2522352</infon><infon key="source">Cell</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">56</infon><infon key="year">1989</infon><offset>76993</offset><text>A three-domain structure of kinesin heavy chain revealed by DNA sequence and microtubule binding analyses</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">42</infon><infon key="lpage">47</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yang;given-names:JT</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Saxton;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Stewart;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Raff;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Goldstein;given-names:L</infon><infon key="source">Nature</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">249</infon><infon key="year">1990</infon><offset>77099</offset><text>Evidence that the head of kinesin is sufficient for force generation and motility in vitro</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">footnote</infon><offset>77190</offset><text>B.D. Manning and J.G. Barrett were supported by National Institutes  of Health (NIH) training grants and NIH grants GM3649 and GM52197,  and this research was funded by NIH grant GM52197.</text></passage></document></collection>
